Guide to the Daniel Brown Papers
Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies
Daniel Brown Papers
1971/1979
This collection contains work papers, mostly related to building the new Plant Sciences Building at the Cary Arboretum, from the 1970's.
10.4 cubic feet (26 boxes)
Brown, Daniel F.
Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies PO Box AB Millbrook, NY 12545-0129 845-677-7600 x164
This collection is open to researchers by appointment only
Daniel Brown was the Capital Projects Coordinator of the Cary Arboretum during the 1970's. He was also the Project Director for Solar Energy work at Cary.
Wells, Malcolm; Lowry, John; Plant Sciences Building; Solar Energy
This collection contains work papers, mostly related to building the new Plant Sciences Building at the Cary Arboretum, from the 1970's. There are lots of letters and building floor plans, many contractor bids, and a focus on renewable energy, like solar.
- Tom Elias Correspondance, 1974 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  " Letters about purchasing a walk-in cooler, insulation standards, budget discussions, planning out potential projects, permit fees, firing people, greenhouse alarm systems, etc
- PBS Planning, 1972 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  " Getting an architect to build the center, including possibly an underground building. Planning projects related to sustainable energy. Environmental considerations in new Cary building, like considering solar. Sewage system plans.
- Ed Setliff Correspondence, 1974 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Discussion of budget concerns.
- Paul Mihan Correspondence, n/a (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Discussion of managing temperature of buildings. History of cold room temp.
- Peter Dykeman Correspondence, 1975 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Info about science lectures at high schools, educational building tours, event attendance lists, office phone issues, volunteer orientation, other newsletters and memos.
- Interoffice Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Info about hunting and fishing rules/permits, and transmission lines. Also includes Cary property maps.
- Paul Marchetti Correspondence, 1974 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  A bunch of little office correspondences.
- Brad Roeller Correspondence, 1976 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Guy Ziliani Correspondence, 1974 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Safety and inventory information.
- Robert Webb Correspondence, 1974 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Maintenance issues, discussions about living research collections and moving around trees.
- David Karnosky Correspondence, 1976 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Correspondences about electrical capacity and Dr Payne visiting the arboretum.
- Win Schubert Correspondence, 1975 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Departmental correspondences regarding development of student programs, energy costs, heating, telephones, repair work, operations department plan and budget, hiring, greenhouse alarm system.
- Library, 1977 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  List of content in the Cary library based on content, into about library tours, bibliographies, operations of library.
- R Biringer Correspondences, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Info on grants and maternity leave.
- Beal/Goldsmith, 1975 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Correspondences about money.
- Purchase Orders & Receipts, 1976 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Purchase Orders, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Maps, n/a (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Also includes doodles of future projects.
- Education Building, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Education building project plans, library and elevator plans.
- Jim Scott + Lee Clark, 1976 - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  More building plans and discussions of cabinets, locks, etc
- Eastern NY Solar Energy Society, 1976 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Newsletters, bylaws, membership records, meeting schedules, discussions of making a northeastern NY chapeter
- Metro Construction Specifications Institute, 1976 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  List of info and resources about greenhouses, preparing a technical aid searches document
- New York State, 1974 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Center for the Hudson River Valley forum invite, solar hot water program, solar grants information
- US Energy Research and Development Administration, 1975 - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  contact information, programs for inventors, solar mailing list information, ERDA organization, small business financial concerns, attempts to gather solar energy projects
- Misc Cary Correspondence, 1975 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Staff health insurance, event information, internal road naming
- Misc NY Botanical Gardens, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  List of employees, employee issues, project proposals
- Miscellaneous, 1974 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Shading projects, greenhouse architect correspondence, correspondences with potential consultant, contractor inspection reports and budgets, other miscellaneous office correspondences
- Telephone Sheets, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Central Hudson, 1975 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Central Hudson service classification, insulation standards
- NY Telephone, 1975 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Correspondences about installing another telephone line
- Staff Memos, 1974 - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  event invitations, memos regarding leave, holidays, jokes, and hunting, administrative staff listing, issues with office use of petty cash
- Howard Irvin, 1975 - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Info about budgets and energy conservation, administrative staff organization, attempts to fund projects, acquiring Gifford house property, solar energy, peer review committee meetings
- Bruning Correspondences, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Contractor Catalogs, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- A & R Building, n/a (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Solar Energy, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  ENYSES, international solar energy society meeting information
- Dr William Payne Correspondences, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  staff policies, PSB planning, fishing privileges, employee complaints, budgeting, memos about William Payne becoming Cary director
- Carlton Lees, 1974 - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  information about porous concrete, Gifford house budget and other renovation info
- Executive Administrator George Bookman, 1976 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  wide variety of office correspondences like, FYI articles, energy events information, meeting agendas, naming of Cary buildings, staff insurance and salary information, and project plans
- Plant Science Building Construction Budgets, 1976 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  budgets and labor rates for arboretum building projects
- T & M Slips, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  change orders
- Progress Photos, 1976 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Building Maintenance, 1977 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Warrants + Guarantees, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  fire alarm, elevator, and water treatment correspondences
- Financial Reports, 1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Also includes budget meeting agendas
- Financial Reports, 1976 - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Furniture Purchase Orders, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Equipment Purchase Orders, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Includes diagrams and info about the dark room
- Furnishing Purchase Orders Approved for Payment, 1977 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  purchase orders for solar heating projects, also includes solar energy magazines
- Site Furniture, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  letters and sketches regarding furniture projects
- Sight Lighting, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Carpet, 1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  bidding, sketches, and specifications
- Environmental Planning + Design, 1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  letters and sketches regarding entrance construction, and other environmental planning and design projects
- Landscaping, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  finances, proposals, and sketches
- R & A Building Committee, 1976 - 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  finances, construction setbacks and progress, sandblazing names into building, meeting schedules, cement mason strike info
- Other Group 3 Purchase Orders, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Malcolm Wells 1, 1975 - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  bid and project decisions, confirmations about smaller aspects of building, architectural sketches, bidding instructions, construction contract conditions, etc
- Malcolm Wells 2, 1976 - 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  payment requests
- Malcolm Wells 3, 1973 - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  letters and memos about building planning, covering topics such as a heat pump, elevator drawings, solar distillation, scheduling, design editing, waster management. Also includes lots of building plans
- Malcolm Wells 4, 1976 - 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  letters about using douglas firs for a deck, door plans, sketches of building changes, plastering info, resolving building problems
- Malcolm Wells 5, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  letters resolving building problems. Also includes promo booklets and hardware schedules
- Malcolm Wells 6, 1976 - 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  kewaunee letters about Cary Arboretum outstanding payments, other letters about feature in architecture magazine and building a conference table. Building sketches and punch list.
- Dublin-Mindell-Bloome Association, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  ERDA-PON proposal, installing telephone lines, contracts, and visitor center plans
- Contracts, 1976 - 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  John Lowry and Malcolm Wells agreements
- Central Hudson, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  letters about the power going out
- Engineer Enis Baskam, 1975 - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  letters about settlement against John Lowry, budgeting, proposals, solar work, architectural portfolios, telephone issues
- BLY Survey, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  staking diagrams
- James Dermody, 1975 - 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  solar energy exhibit sketches, energy report, information for museums
- Sylvan Shemitz, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  correspondences about lighting design and electrical engineering; invoices, time sheets, and drawings
- Sylvan Shemitz 2, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  invoices, drawings, and time sheets
- Interspace Inc, 1976 - 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  cabinet info, billing drawings, options, and overall interior design proposal
- Interspace Inc 2, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  bills, floor plans, and other interior design papers
- Dubin-Bloome, 1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  building intrastructure, corrosion and water issues; floor plans
- Millwork, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  bidding documents for cabinet work
- Kewaunee, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  lab equipment sketches, budgets, and specifications
- Sylvan Shemitz, 1975 - 1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  lighting budgets, bills & invoices, proposals, sketches, bids, and planning
- Automatic Controls, 1976 - 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  bid proposals, heating system seminar notes, product booklets, correspondence log, more papers about heating and air conditioning
- Change Order Requests and Proposals, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Rejected Change Order Proposals, 1976 - 1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  submitted proposals that include budgets and sketches
- Approved Changed Orders 1-25, 1975 - 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  copies of change order breakdowns, building changes
- Approved CO 25-50, 1976 - 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Approved CO 51-75, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Approved CO 76-100, 1977 - 1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Requisitions 1-10, 1976 - 1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  payments, taxes, invoices, requisition detail statement
- Requisitions 11-20, 1977 - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Requisitions 20-25, 1977 - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Corrective Work, 1977 - 1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  architectural punch list, job report, related memos and letters
- John Lowry, 1976 - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  keying schedule, small building issues, meeting follow-ups, drawings, insurance certificates, troubleshooting, buds, cement mason strike info
- John Lowry, 1978 - 1979 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Mostly letters negotiating when to pay bills, other budget concerns, and troubleshooting
- John Lowry, 1976 - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  fume hood discussions, awarding bids for building, conference table payments, contracts and insurance letters
- John Lowry, 1977 - 1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Court case papers (John Lowry vs Cary Arboretum), meeting plans, small developments with PSB building, notary
- ETA Grant Solicitation, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  budgeting, grant proposals (including to US department of labor), Solar Utilization Economic Development and Employment, conference schedule
- Methane Plant, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  letters and plans regarding the development of an educational plant, energy tracking and requirements
- Electra Supply, 1976 - 1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  information about lamps, legal dispute with Electra, bills, proposals, floorpans, purchase orders, product descriptions
- PSB Operating Budget, 1978 - 1979 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  mostly papers related to insurance
- Interoffice Correspondence, 1977 - 1979 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  paycheck issues, John Lowry legal issues, miscellaneous correspondences, building problems, presentation prep, making and planning payments, potential BOCES involvement with PSB
- Interoffice Correspondence, 1974 - 1976 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  furniture bids, meeting minutes, conference table, papers about a documentary made for Cary, papers about building,ding entrance and groundbreaking ceremony, budgeting
- Miscellaneous, 1975 - 1978 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  dutchess community college high school architecture contest, editing article about PSB, touring information and correspondences, letters inquiring about PSB
- Miscellaneous, 1972 - 1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  thank you notes, letters about energy usage, giving tours, building materials, and proposals
- Dublin-Mindell-Bloome Associates, 1976 - 1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  solar energy, building floor plans, air filtering, energy consumption,
- Dublin-Mindell-Bloome Associates, 1974 - 1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  correspondences with engineer, greenhouse, solar energy, product flyers, maps, water testing, budget tables
- Dublin-Mindell-Bloome Associates, 1973 - 1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  similar to other DMBA correspondences, includes House of Representatives Subcommittee testimony
- Meeting Minutes, 1974 - 1978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Meeting minutes, some more casual letters
- Estimates, 1975 - 1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  building costs, detailed budget authorization requests, requests for ERDA money, furniture costs
- Specifications + Estimates, 1974 - 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Field Orders, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  small changes to the building process
- Daily Reports, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Selected Contractor Lists, 1974 - 1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  contractor contact info broken down by specialty, reports on each potential contractor
- Test Reports, 1973 - 1975 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  proposals to test construction materials, well and water testing reports, testing specifications
- Product Data + Materials File, 1974
  wood samples, descriptions, and testing
- Selected Prime Contractors, 1974 - 1975 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  letters, qualification statements, and promo booklets for contractors, including John Lowry
- Permits, 1974 - 1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  pollution, zoning, building and sewage permits. Also includes maps and sketches.
- Minutes of Lowry Coordination Meetings, 1976 - 1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  updates on different parts of business project
- Gifford House Renovations, 1977 - 1978 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  sketches, carpet samples, road work permit, door schedule, item orders and proposals
- Gifford House Invoices + Blueprints, 1975 - 1977 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  water well reports, invoices, sketches, proposals and bid prices, products catalogs, etc
- Gifford House Invoices + Blueprints, 1975 - 1979 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  letters about Gifford house budget, status report about capital projects, cash flow and project cost records, Gifford house correspondences, product catalogs, purchase orders
- Fan and Pad System, 1977 - 1978 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  cooling system cost, letters, proposals, and product catalogs
- Critical Path Method, 1975 - 1976 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  company resumes and info, writings about PSB
- Post-bid Correspondence, 1973 - 1975 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  balance sheet, possible cost savings, meeting notes
- Rejected Electrical Subcontractors, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  copies of rejected bid proposals
- Selected Mechanical Subcontractors, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Selected Electrical Subcontractors, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Pre-bid correspondences, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  requested specifications for bids, along with other correspondences
- Addenda, 1975 - 1976 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  floor plans, revised building information (w/sketches), and letters about aid due dates
- Rejected Prime Contractors, 1975 - 1976 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Rejected Mechanical Subcontractors, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Education Center, 1975 - 1976 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  building plans and permit, lab furnishings, product catalogs, health department test results, etc
- Education Center, 1975 - 1976 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  topics covered include building plans, acid disposal, interior design, pricing, lumber orders, and contract with architect
- Window Changes, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  plans and sketches for windows
- Computer Center, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  letters, product catalogs, and sketches
- C-Drawings, 1976 - 1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  building sketches and letters about wall planning
- Inventory, n/a (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Xerox, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  also includes some building specifications and sketches
- Main Floor Plans, 1976 - 1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Transmittals, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  concerning small building issues
- All-Steel, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  furniture orders, product catalog
- Lab Purchase Orders, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Planters Letters + Purchase Orders, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Conference Table, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  sketches + letters
- Women's Lounge, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  planning letters
- Kewaunee, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  sketches + letters about purchasing furniture
- Kewaunee Fixtures, n/a (Box 22, Folder 14)
  sketches, lab furnishings, product catalogs, letters
- Jim Dugan, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  sketches, letters, and furniture concerns
- Dave Deppen, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  fixture sketches and letters
- Lab Equipment, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  product catalogs, pricing, letters, bids
- Latest Color Code, n/a (Box 22, Folder 18)
  color coded building plans
- Miscellaneous PSB Changes, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  building plans, some letters regarding changes
- Field Sketches, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Equipment, n/a (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Lighting Catalogs, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Mechanical Catalogs, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  also information from contractors
- Furnishing Catalogs, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Library Equipment Catalogs, 1975 - 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Specialty Catalogs, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  mostly paint catalogs
- Door & Window Catalogs, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Thermal and Moisture Protection Catalogs, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Lath Houses, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  pricing and insurance sheets, product catalogs, progress schedule, shade house punch list
- Maintenance Center, 1975 - 1976 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  budgeting, bid acceptance, building plans, architect proposal, site evaluation, product catalog
- Site Plans, n/a (Box 23, Folder 12)
- General Sitework, n/a (Box 24, Folder 1)
  underground primary service at the nursery
- Lath House, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  electrical plans, product catalogs, pricing, shade house punch list, progress schedule
- Sitework, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  also includes sketches, pricing, and papers about signs
- Solar Collectors, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  payments for bid submissions
- Automatic Controls, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  includes addenda and bid due dates
- Interspace, n/a (Box 24, Folder 6)
  ecology lab building plans
- Mac Wells A & R Building, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Interspace -Furnishing, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  furniture orders and lists, product catalogs, building plans
- Mailroom, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  building plans, letters, product catalogs, quotes
- Building Plans/Product Catalog, n/a (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Carpet, n/a (Box 24, Folder 11)
  floor plans, bid information
- Capital Cabinet Letters, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Horticulture, 1976 - 1977 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  floor plans, product catalogs, letters
- Upholstery, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  pricing notes
- Confirmation Purchase Orders, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  mostly for steel
- PO to be Written, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  list of furniture orders and prices
- Backup, 1976 - 1977 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  quotes, price listings, purchase orders and summaries
- Budget-Furnishings, 1976 - 1977 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  also includes budget quotes from companies
- Library Furnishings, 1976 - 1977 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  orders and budgets, floor plan, item listings, product catalogs, wood sample
- Wiltse Brothers, 1975 - 1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Wilste brothers are grading and excavating contractors. Papers discuss building insurance proposal, site maps, construction drawings, and contractor qualifications
- Sitework Bid Stage, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  development, grading, and excavation bids.
- Permits, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  road work permit with site plan
- Interoffice Co, 1974 - 1975 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  sitework, tree locations, and excavation plans
- Construction and Sitework Estimates, 1974 - 1975 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Sitework specifications, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  site work proposal request
- Nursery-Greenhouse, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  proposal acceptances, security info, floor plans, product sheet, pricing catalog
- Nursery-Greenhouse Paving, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  site plans and memos
- Construction, 1976 - 1977 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  leaking issues, approved proposals, water analysis, floor plans, door schedule, burying a cable, equipment quotes
- Gifford --Demolition, 1975 - 1976 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  product catalogs, furniture to remove from Gifford house, repaired, lab furniture
- A & R Sitework, 1974 - 1975 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  administrative evaluations and research sit map
- John Lowry Sitework, 1971 - 1976 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  bid changes, contract conditions, agreement between owner and contractor, prices, change orders, and meeting notes
- PSB Specifications, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  sample building project conditions, list of necessary contracts documents
- Furniture Approval Letters, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  purchase orders and notes on furniture
- ERDA PON DSE 75-2, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  ERDA=Energy Research and Development Administration, PON equals Program Opportunity Notice, building sketches, bidding proposals
- ERDA PON DSE 75-2, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  more proposals, including response proposals for fund requests from government. dialogues with congress and NY state assembly, financial statements, revising rejected proposal
- Electrical Catalogs, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  electrical, hardware, and security product lists and catalogs, metal and glass samples, info about lighting and electrical outlets